<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sessions>
  <flow>
    <title>Decolonizing Bodies: Yoga For POCs</title>
    <shortdesc>&#34;Caring for myself is not self-indulgence, it is self-preservation, and that is an act of political warfare.&#34; – Audre Lorde. Come engage in a practice of individual and communal self-care in an all-levels, body-positive, trans and queer adoring, hairy, abundant, yoga class for folks of colour and indigenous folks.  Laughter and questions are encouraged as is space for silence. Led by a registered yoga teacher queer femme survivor with over 8 years of experience.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 1243 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Kim Crosby, Brown Girl&#039;s Yoga/The People Project/The Brown Grrlz Project</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>adults only</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#pocyoga</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7005</shortlink>
    <tracks>Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>8:00am - 8:45am / Early sessions</schedblock>
    <title>Pre-conference Healing: Yoga</title>
    <shortdesc>Join us for healing and yoga--one of the world&#039;s oldest ways of connecting and transforming our bodies. Led as a pre-conference session for all-bodies and all levels of experience, the Healing Justice Practice Space wants you to move through the conference feeling great.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room F/G (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Healing Justice Practice Space</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCHeal</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7192</shortlink>
    <tracks>Healing Justice Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>8:00am - 8:45am / Early sessions</schedblock>
    <title>Shawty Got Skillz Skillshare!</title>
    <shortdesc>In the 4th Shawty Got Skillz Skillshare, we continue to amplify the message that we have what we need to create the world we want! Participants will go from station to station, learning media skills and making connections to the work we are already doing in our communities. Skillz include: How to wrap media on your body, Transmedia Storytelling, Mande Dance, How to Cast a Love Spell, DJ Geek Out, &#039;Automated Automatic&#039;: Managing your social web, Creating accessible movement spaces, and so much more! Start where ever you want and stay at each station as long as you&#039;d like.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry A (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Moya Bailey, Crunk Feminist Collective; Cherry Galette, Mangos With Chili; Zachari J. Curtis, DC Black Growers&#039; Network/Afroqueerizedbeekeeper; Leah Lakshmi Piepzna-Samarasinha, Mangos With Chili; Alexis Pauline Gumbs, Mobile Homecoming/Eternal Summer of the Black Feminist Mind; Adaku, SouLar Bliss; Kristina Gray, DJ Geekout; Zuri Murphy, BLOCS; jess solomon, The Saartjie Project; Kismet/Jessica, The LatiNegr@s Project, Quirky Black Girls, iwannalive productions, Betta Come Correct Collective (and SGSZ!); Holiday Simmons, Lambda Legal, Georgia Safe Schools Coalition, Trans(Forming)</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#sgsz</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6994</shortlink>
    <tracks>Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space, Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space, Analog Media Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Open Source Virtual Worlds 101</title>
    <shortdesc>Create your own massively multiplayer online game (MMOG) world. Opensimulator.org technology is free and open-source. It can be used to create virtual world simulations that up to now have only be possible with expensive technology. There are two sessions: 101 is how to use your avatar to create the virtual world of your dreams. All you need is a mouse and access to someone&#039;s server. 201 is the boring stuff which you or that other person will have to do to set up the server. Or, in either session, you can download a pre-built zip file to let you run the whole thing yourself from a USB stick.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room L (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Paul Emery, 3dcolab.com, virtualdetroit.org</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#Sim101</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6985</shortlink>
    <tracks>Imagining Better Futures Through Play Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Nerd Party: Creating an Engaging Website</title>
    <shortdesc>Blogging, Facebook, and Twitter are some of the fastest ways to reach out and involve new people in a project or community, but it can be a challenge to figure out where to start and how to use these tools.  Learn the different options available for creating a website, basic design concepts and HTML, best practices for blogging/creating content, how to build a community online, along with ways to integrate and use Facebook, Twitter and other social media sites. Laptops/tablets will be helpful, but not required.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room J (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Sarah Morgan, xoSarah Design, The Weird Sisters Circus</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#nerdparty</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7000</shortlink>
    <tracks>Webmaking Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Build Your Own Mini Radio Transmitter</title>
    <shortdesc>Building a radio transmitter is a great way to learn about basic electronics and prepare to occupy the airwaves! In this hands-on workshop, we&#039;ll talk about the theory behind radio transmission and start building our own ultra-low-power transmitters. No radio or electronics background is needed! You can return to the media lab later in the conference to continue building your transmitter – expect to spend about two hours after the workshop finishing it.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room B/C (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Maggie Avener, Prometheus Radio Project</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#mini-radio</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6997</shortlink>
    <tracks>Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space, Occupy the Airwaves! Community Radio Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Re-imagining Education in Urban Spaces</title>
    <shortdesc>In this session, educators, students, and media artists from the Detroit Future Schools program will share their experiences in looking to re-invent education in urban spaces, offering not only new visions of reform, but also transformative processes that they used in classrooms along with student-generated media projects. DFS pairs digital media artists with teachers to develop curricula that integrates media &#38; technology into the learning experience, with hopes to foster stronger connections to community and an increased sense of agency.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 157 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Isaac Miller, Detroit Future Schools/InsideOut Literary Arts Project; Ammerah Saidi, Detroit Future Schools; Danielle Filipiak, Detroit Public Schools</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#reskool</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7020</shortlink>
    <tracks>Research Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Queer &#38; Trans Storytelling in the South</title>
    <shortdesc>Building on the cultural traditions of resistance and storytelling in the South, two organizations will explore social justice organizing and healing initiatives through the use of video, audio, and photography. BreakOUT!, an organization that fights the criminalization of LGBTQ youth in New Orleans, LA, will discuss their &#34;We Deserve Better&#34; campaign and video. Lambda Legal&#039;s Southern Regional Office in Atlanta, GA will showcase their &#34;Trans Tell Your Story Project&#34; which documents the stories of transgender and gender non-conforming people in the metro Atlanta area.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 2242 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Holiday Simmons, Lambda Legal; Wes Ware, Break OUT!</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#storytime</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7032</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Media Policy for Love and Justice Track, Analog Media Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Radio as an organizing tool</title>
    <shortdesc>Come learn about using radio as an organizing tool with Migrant Justice, the Vermont Workers&#039; Center, and the Media Mobilizing Project!</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry B (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Milena Velis, Media Mobilizing Project; Megan Sheehan, Vermont Workers&#039; Center; Natalia Fajardo, Migrant Justice/Justicia Migrante; Danilo Lopez, Migrant Justice/Justicia Migrante</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#orgradio</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7054</shortlink>
    <tracks>Occupy the Airwaves! Community Radio Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Mobile Justice: The Next Frontier</title>
    <shortdesc>Mobile devices have become the primary means that youth, communities of color and low-wealth communities use to access the Internet. This new form of Internet access is facing a number of emerging threats due to consolidation in the mobile industry and government policies that favor big corporations over our communities. Join us to learn how national, regional and local organizations came together to stop a merger between AT&#38;T and T-Mobile that many thought was inevitable. An interactive timeline will show us lessons we need to pursue policies that protect our communities.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room M (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Steven Renderos, Center for Media Justice; Chancellar Williams, Free Press; Parul Desai, Consumers Union; Kira Shepherd, Color of Change; Jamilah King, Colorlines</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>adults only</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#mobilejust</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7151</shortlink>
    <tracks>Media Policy for Love and Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Silkscreening in Abundance!</title>
    <shortdesc>Silkscreening for the Masses! A primer course.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 156/158 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Bec Young, Justseeds Artists&#039; Cooperative</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#silkscreen</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7097</shortlink>
    <tracks>Transformative Art Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Finding Voice with People in Prison</title>
    <shortdesc>Discuss creative and transformative research and writing methods for people living in prison.  Prison creates obstacles around information sharing and gathering techniques, but there are ways to develop long and lasting relationships with people inside. We will present tools and lead discussion on ways to develop public messaging campaigns that highlight collaborative writing and research practices with people living in our state prisons, and to shed light on conditions and work towards reform.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 154 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Natalie Holbrook, American Friends Service Committee Michigan Criminal Justice Program; Peter Martel, American Friends Service Committee Michigan Criminal Justice Program; Tashiena Combs</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#FindVoice</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7108</shortlink>
    <tracks>Research Justice Track, Analog Media Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Get It Right: Research, Power, and Community</title>
    <shortdesc>How can communities ensure that they have a voice in what is said about them, how they are portrayed, and how (and by whom) their data is collected, used, and stored? In this session we will discuss ways to give researched people more power over research, offering tools and strategies for greater community control.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 1243 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Eric Wat (Presenter), Services for Special Groups (SSG), Los Angeles; Jessi Quizar (Presenter), University of Southern California, INCITE!; Monica White, Detroit Black Community Food Security Network (DBCFSN); Jenny Lee (Moderator), Allied Media Projects</presorgs>
    <seshtype>strategy session</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#CommIRB</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7115</shortlink>
    <tracks>Research Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Son Jarocho: Iniciando un Movimiento</title>
    <shortdesc>Son Jarocho is a music/dance form rooted in indigenous, Mexican and African cultures melded together in Veracruz, Mexico. Like hip-hop, it is a genre birthed out of struggle, building community as it grows. From teaching to performance practices, Son Jarocho is all inclusive and empowering. It lends itself naturally to community organizing as it breeds community.  Participants in this workshop will get a break down of the percussive aspects of Son Jarocho, in particular zapateado, and better understand how Son Jarocho is a transformative artform.</shortdesc>
    <location>Community Arts Auditorium</location>
    <presorgs>Camilo Rincon, Jarochicanos; Maya Fernandez, Jarochicanos; Adrian Alcantar, Jarochicanos; Laura Cambron</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#sonviva</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7133</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Media History Timeline</title>
    <shortdesc>This workshop explores the power of media in reflecting and shaping our society. It allows us to look at our history to inform our current and future media making and place our work within the context of social justice movements. This workshop highlights the important role media plays in analyzing power in the U.S. by looking at historical moments to frame our understanding of why we need to be creating media from a social justice perspective. Folks will take part in Interactive Timeline, Media Ownership Relay Race, sharing of personal histories, and media viewing.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry C (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Adriel Grant, Charles Canario, Batala Aristide, Isabel Villalba, Reyni Almonte, Stefanie Ureña, Teresa Basilio, Sasha Goldberg, Global Action Project (G.A.P.)</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#gapmedia</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7138</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation)</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Healing Justice Individual Session 3</title>
    <shortdesc>Come to the HJPS during Individual Session 3 on sustainability tune-ups, intuitive healing, massage, Somatic Bodywork, Reiki, Herbalism, Acupuncture and Counseling.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room F/G (McGregor)</location>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCHeal</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7188</shortlink>
    <tracks>Healing Justice Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Earth Power: Field Trip to Earthworks Urban Farm</title>
    <shortdesc>Planting! Weeding! Watering! Harvesting! From seed, to flower, to fruit, to food for us, to compost, we’ll learn about the glorious food cycle and our place in it. We will take 2-3 vans of kids and travel there for the first two sessions on Saturday, arriving back at Wayne State for lunch. (Field trip form required)</shortdesc>
    <location>North Side of McGregor</location>
    <presorgs>Lauren Karchmer, Intergalactic Conspiracy of Childcare Collectives</presorgs>
    <seshtype>Detroit tours</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for kids!</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#amckids</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7215</shortlink>
    <tracks>Kids Transform The World</tracks>
    <schedblock>9:00am - 10:30am / Block 5</schedblock>
    <title>Graphic Campaigns for All</title>
    <shortdesc>Learn to work together to create dynamic and fun graphic campaigns that reflect the needs and demands of our communities. Have you ever attempted to make a poster and felt like you didn&#039;t have enough tools or experience? How about a banner? The copy machine is broken and you don&#039;t know how to make a flyer for your event? Join this fun hands-on session where everyone will have a go at solving all these issues, and get ready to print, paint, cut, carve, design, draw, and come up with ideas collectively.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 156/158 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Santiago Armengod, Justseeds, Medios Caminantes, ECPM68, La Otra Grafika; Bec Young, Justseeds</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#Graphics</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6989</shortlink>
    <tracks>Transformative Art Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Culture Shift: One Story at a Time</title>
    <shortdesc>We are the 77.5%! In the 2000 Census, only 22.5% of households classified themselves as 2 heterosexual parents and 2 biological children. So, why does this traditional definition of family continue to dominate social debate and policy making? We need to interrupt this dominant narrative and redefine family in our terms! Participants will hear about storytelling as a strategy to do just that. They will share their own stories, and from the Strong Families model, learn how story telling can be used to shift culture, shape campaigns, and build collaborations across sectors.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 154 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Shanelle Matthews, Forward Together (formerly Asian Communities for Reproductive Justice); Tavae Samuelu, Forward Together (formerly Asian Communities for Reproductive Justice)</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#strongfam</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7012</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Research Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Open Source Virtual Worlds 201</title>
    <shortdesc>Create your own massively multiplayer online game (MMOG) world. Opensimulator.org technology is free and open-source. It can be used to create virtual world simulations that up to now have only be possible with expensive technology. There are two sessions: 101 is how to use your avatar to create the virtual world of your dreams. All you need is a mouse and access to someone&#039;s server. 201 is the boring stuff which you or that other person will have to do to set up the server. Or, in either session, you can download a pre-built zip file to let you run the whole thing yourself from a USB stick.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room L (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Paul Emery, 3dcolab.com, virtualdetroit.org</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#OSSim201</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7029</shortlink>
    <tracks>Imagining Better Futures Through Play Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Low Power to the People: How to get LPFM</title>
    <shortdesc>The recent passage of the Local Community Radio Act was the culmination of a successful ten-year organizing campaign by Prometheus Radio Project and media justice groups to give ordinary people a voice over the airwaves. Later this year nonprofit organizations across the country will have a historic opportunity to apply for thousands of new low power FM radio licenses, including availability for the first time in urban areas!</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry B (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Vanessa Maria Graber, Prometheus Radio Project; Ana Martina Rivas, Prometheus Radio Project</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>adults only</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#LPFM2012</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7062</shortlink>
    <tracks>Occupy the Airwaves! Community Radio Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>National Strategy For Black Gay Youth &#38; Out in the System</title>
    <shortdesc>Nearly 2,000 black gay youth from all over the United States completed a national needs assessment detailing what it is like to grow up black and gay in America in an effort to promote the need for structural change for the mental and physical health of black gay youth in this country. Code Red performs stories collected from the National Strategy For Black Gay Youth In America. Through one-on-one to small group exercises, participants are able to show how incorporating LGBTQ youth stories into actions of advocacy can not only benefit LGBTQ youth but also the individual and collective service providers on best practices and community building.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry C (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Frank Walker, Youth Pride Services; Henry Walker, Ruth Ellis Center</presorgs>
    <seshtype>performance</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#CodeRed</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7072</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>PowerBase: Open + Community Source</title>
    <shortdesc>The ends do not justify the means. How you do something is as important, if not more important, than the end result. When the Progressive Technology Project (PTP) was given a mandate from its constituency: &#34;Tell us what database to use,&#34; we decided to embark on a very deliberate process that has led to the development of a database (PowerBase) specifically for folks doing community organizing. Come chat with us about what we have learned from this process and why it is vital for organizers and developers to work together to create the tools that support social change.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 157 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Josue Guillen, Progressive Technology Project</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#PowerBase</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7073</shortlink>
    <tracks>Webmaking Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Youth Perspectives through Blogging &#38; Vlogging</title>
    <shortdesc>Youth leaders at the F.A.M.E. (Freeing A Mind Everywhere) program at Vanguard CDC in Detroit have begun using blogging and vlogging to strategically share unheard youth perspectives about their struggles and visions in their neighborhood.  Learn new techniques that will help you ask the right questions that draw out authentic stories from community members about issues impacting their community, and solutions from the people most affected by them. Participants will be supported as they create their own blog/vlog entry and post it as part of the session.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 1243 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Domonique Baul, Vanguard Community Development Corporation; F.A.M.E. Leadership Council, Vanguard Community Development Corporation</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#DFY</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7077</shortlink>
    <tracks>Webmaking Track, Media Policy for Love and Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>DJ Geekout</title>
    <shortdesc>Inspired by innovative parties in DC, Philly, Detroit &#38; living room jams that include pecha kucha, vinyl sharing, &#38; storytelling - the DJ Geekout was born as a way to re-imagine the dance floor &#38; reshape the role of the DJ. Led by a diverse group of DJ&#039;s, we are visioning &#38; discovering how we live the art of DJing – as the power &#38; responsibility to cultivate and sustain spaces, make community connections, &#38; create change that there&#039;s little language for. Join the party and start your own movement!</shortdesc>
    <location>Community Arts Auditorium</location>
    <presorgs>bent, Junebullet, K La Rock, Mothershiester, Natty Boom, Nina Colada, Pinstriped Rebel, PreColumbian, rAt, Ripley, Brian Senyo, Trash, Zombie + others TBA, Our Geekout Crew reps many parties and crews across the country including Anthology of Booty, Maracuyeah, She.Rex, First Ladies, Girls Rock DC, Swenka, Radio Estrogeno, Surya Dub, Radio CPR, and more</presorgs>
    <seshtype>performance</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#djgeekout</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7098</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Blogging in Prison with Between the Bars</title>
    <shortdesc>Having no access to the Internet, incarcerated individuals are excluded from the public discourse occurring on the most important platform since the printing press.  This session shares the broadcast media tool &#34;Between the Bars&#34; which enables people in prison to express themselves creatively through blogging via paper mail.  Participants will learn how to post content on a writer&#039;s behalf from scanning and uploading, through processing and publishing.  Organizations working within prisons will learn how to allow their constituents to blog as a discrete group they manage.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room B/C (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Benjamin Sugar, Between the Bars; Carl McClaren, Between the Bars; Charlie DeTar, Between the Bars</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#btbamc2012</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7113</shortlink>
    <tracks>Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Batphone 4: Disaster, Resistance &#38; The Win</title>
    <shortdesc>Disaster, unrest and economic inequity leave one third of the global population without access to telecommunications infrastructure at any given point. The Batphone software offers a solution for these communities by enabling an off-the-shelf mobile handset to automatically create its own communication network with any similar device. Calls can be made from one handset to the next without needing  the wires and transmission equipment that traditional telecommunications require.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room J (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Xavier Leonard, Designers for Humanity; Bea Alvarez, Fab Lab San Diego; June Clarke</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#Batphone</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7116</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Art, Gentrification, and Our Broken Beautiful Cities*</title>
    <shortdesc>Detroit and New Orleans have for decades competed for the &#34;Murder Capital&#34; title, among many other negative stigmas under the mass media lens. Somehow &#34;Chocolate City&#34; has become synonymous with crime, corruption and violence. Yet, those who call these cities home are not only witnessing, but are a part of some of the most innovative and sustainable solutions to the complete re-building of their communities quite literally from the ground-up post-disaster. Session leaders from groups active in each city, such as Kids ReThink New Orleans Schools, 2-Cent TV, Youth BreakOUT, Urban Bush Women, Detroit Future Schools, Detroit Future Media and more will share experiences with alternative solutions to absentee economic development, gentrification, perceptions of public art and confronting mass media stigmas of our communities. We will explore shared challenges and unique solutions between the two cities in a fishbowl style forum facilitated by Gia Hamilton and Jocelyne Ninneman of Gris Gris Lab. *The title of this session is a nod to Alexis Pauline Gumbs and Broken Beautiful Press!</shortdesc>
    <location>Room M (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Jocelyne m. Ninneman, Pont:Productions / Gris Gris Lab / Detroit Sound Conservancy; Gia M. Hamilton, Gris Gris Lab</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#NOLA2ThaD</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7142</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Transformative Art Practice Space, Media Policy for Love and Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>From Third Cinema to Media Justice</title>
    <shortdesc>Using the reanimated archive of Third World Majority, one of the first women of color media collectives in the country, we will present more than just a history session. Using new ideas, tools, and processes for artists and media-makers we will examine ways to deepen their collaboration and theoretical engagement in various media forms. Participants should come planning to share work and their ideas behind their work.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 2242 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Thenmozhi Soundararajan, Dalit Diva Productions; Kara Keeling</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#3rdcinema</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7166</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation)</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Shawty Got Skillz Skillshare! (Continued)</title>
    <shortdesc>In the 4th Shawty Got Skillz Skillshare, we continue to amplify the message that we have what we need to create the world we want! Participants will go from station to station, learning media skills and making connections to the work we are already doing in our communities. Skillz include: How to wrap media on your body, Transmedia Storytelling, Mande Dance, How to Cast a Love Spell, DJ Geek Out, &#039;Automated Automatic&#039;: Managing your social web, Creating accessible movement spaces, and so much more! Start where ever you want and stay at each station as long as you&#039;d like.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry A (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Moya Bailey, Crunk Feminist Collective; Cherry Galette, Mangos With Chili; Zachari J. Curtis, DC Black Growers&#039; Network/Afroqueerizedbeekeeper; Leah Lakshmi Piepzna-Samarasinha, Mangos With Chili; Alexis Pauline Gumbs, Mobile Homecoming/Eternal Summer of the Black Feminist Mind; Adaku, SouLar Bliss; Kristina Gray, DJ Geekout; Zuri Murphy, BLOCS; jess solomon, The Saartjie Project; Kismet/Jessica, The LatiNegr@s Project, Quirky Black Girls, iwannalive productions, Betta Come Correct Collective (and SGSZ!); Holiday Simmons, Lambda Legal, Georgia Safe Schools Coalition, Trans(Forming)</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#sgsz</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7239</shortlink>
    <tracks>Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space, Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space, Analog Media Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Earth Power: Field Trip to Earthworks Urban Farm (Continued)</title>
    <shortdesc>Planting! Weeding! Watering! Harvesting! From seed, to flower, to fruit, to food for us, to compost, we’ll learn about the glorious food cycle and our place in it. We will take 2-3 vans of kids and travel there for the first two sessions on Saturday, arriving back at Wayne State for lunch. (Field trip form required)</shortdesc>
    <location>Off-site</location>
    <presorgs>Lauren Karchmer, Intergalactic Conspiracy of Childcare Collectives</presorgs>
    <seshtype>Detroit tours</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for kids!</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#amckids</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7245</shortlink>
    <tracks>Kids Transform The World</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Healing Justice Individual Session 4</title>
    <shortdesc>Come to the HJPS during Individual Session 4 for self-restoration, healing and information!</shortdesc>
    <location>Room F/G (McGregor)</location>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCHeal</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7261</shortlink>
    <tracks>Healing Justice Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>11:00am - 12:30pm / Block 6</schedblock>
    <title>Healing: Looking Beyond Medical Systems</title>
    <shortdesc>We invite you to share stories, gather information, build strategies across distance that deal with sickness and disability. We will discuss how media (blogs, social media, search engines) can be used to create a grassroots movement of people looking beyond the medical system/challenging the medical system/building solidarity with each other. We will talk about challenges, needs and strategies people with disability and sickness issues have used to cope, heal and build.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 1243 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Anandi Wonder; Chiara Galimberti</presorgs>
    <seshtype>1 hour caucus (lunch-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#ourhealth</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6979</shortlink>
    <tracks>Healing Justice Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>12:30pm - 2:00pm / SAT LUNCH BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Collective Dream: QT2SPOC Performer Caucus</title>
    <shortdesc>This caucus  will be a space for queer, trans and Two Spirit performers of color who are part of or interested in forming a QT2SPOC performance collective. Participants will emerge with a stronger network, skills, media resources, and collaboration opportunities to change the world through radical queer and trans, Two Spirit, POC cultural production.  We encourage folks to bring zines, websites, Tumblrs, blogs, posters, postcards, podcasts and any and all media tools and skills to share.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 154 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Leah Lakshmi Piepzna-Samarasinha, Mangos With Chili; Cherry Galette, Mangos With Chili</presorgs>
    <seshtype>1 hour caucus (lunch-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#qtpocperf</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7050</shortlink>
    <tracks>Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>12:30pm - 2:00pm / SAT LUNCH BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Wordpress for Community Organizers</title>
    <shortdesc>What does equity look like in digital spaces, and how is it threatened by Internet censorship and corporatization? How can activists and community organizers utilize open-source software like Wordpress to create accessible web-based platforms for discussion, analysis, and knowledge dissemination? This caucus will engage participants in an open discussion on how Wordpress and similar open-source technologies can create accessible avenues for equity and participation within the digital sphere.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry A (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Sidra Mahmood, OneSeventyFive.com</presorgs>
    <seshtype>1 hour caucus (lunch-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#wordpress</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7089</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Webmaking Track, Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>12:30pm - 2:00pm / SAT LUNCH BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>People of Color Radio Caucus - Get on the Air!</title>
    <shortdesc>Color of Change, the largest online Black advocacy group in the country, with over 800,000 members nationwide, is expanding our work to support people of color to build community radio stations. How can groups support the expansion of community radio in their communities and help people of color get on the air? How can we build robust social networks and independent media infrastructure that we own and control?</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry B (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Jeff Rousset, Prometheus Radio Project</presorgs>
    <seshtype>1 hour caucus (lunch-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCRadio</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7237</shortlink>
    <tracks>Occupy the Airwaves! Community Radio Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>12:30pm - 2:00pm / SAT LUNCH BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Tour Your Art: Make More Living Room</title>
    <shortdesc>This is a walk-through of the nation-wide salon-styled poetry tour, The Revival. Enjoy new work from touring poets and musicians. Discuss the ups and downs of life as an independent artist on the road. Engage with producer, Jade Foster, on why independent traveling artists are necessary and some tips on doing it yourself!</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 154 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Jade Foster, CEREUS ARTS</presorgs>
    <seshtype>performance</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#REVIVE</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6986</shortlink>
    <tracks>Transformative Art Practice Space, Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space, Collective Access Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Hurricane Season Curriculum</title>
    <shortdesc>Climbing PoeTree’s Hurricane Season curriculum employs art and culture to help learners analyze systems of oppression and resistance, and build leadership essential for radical social change. The curriculum development team will share the process and pedagogy of translating a performance into an interdisciplinary course, and offer training in one sample lesson plan. Participants will learn valuable facilitation skills including how to incorporate interactive activities, art, media, dialogue, theatre of the oppressed, research, and project-based learning into educational environments.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry B (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Naima Penniman, Climbing PoeTree, Ayiti Resurrect; Angelique Nixon, International Resource Network (Caribbean Region Board), Ayiti Resurrect; Samara Gaev, Project Rhythm, Question Bridge, In Transition Hip Hop Theatre Co., Brooklyn Academy of Music; Beatrice Anderson, Ifetayo, Jazz at Lincoln Center, Urban Arts Partnership, Metropolitan Opera, Midori and Friends; Carlos Pittella Leite, World of Ideas, Global Citizenship Experience, One to Trees</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#popEd</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7002</shortlink>
    <tracks>Research Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Connective Tissue: Organizing Embodied</title>
    <shortdesc>This workshop explores how we can build successful social movements that will not only win campaign victories but also transform the systemic roots of trauma. Through collaborative exercises we will practice body awareness and somatic healing techniques, and share strategies for incorporating embodied practices into our organizing work.</shortdesc>
    <location>Community Arts Auditorium</location>
    <presorgs>Anna Martine Whitehead, M//M; Lily Dunham-Hughes, M//M</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>adults only</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#embodied</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7010</shortlink>
    <tracks>Healing Justice Practice Space, Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Beatboxing</title>
    <shortdesc>In a digital world of non-stop music discovery, it is important to remember the origins of music and the traditional techniques and styles of how music is made. Beatboxing is a sometimes-forgotten medium that still plays an important role in the production world. In this session we will discuss how beaboxing began, where beatboxing is going, and how it can stay relevant in this digital age. We will also get hands on and learn to beatbox. Get excited because by the end of this session we will be recording a jam for the whole AMC conference to hear!</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry A (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Mr. Stevie, Beatbox Master</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#BeatboxAMC</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6995</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Civic Hacking for Self Governance</title>
    <shortdesc>Civic hacking is a term that usually describes technologies that make government more efficient, open and democratic.  This panel will reinterpret &#34;hacking&#34; to mean any process that intervenes in systems of governance to redraw relationships of power and decision-making, including, but not limited to, technological interventions.  We&#039;ll look at participatory budgeting as one non-digital example of civic hacking.  We&#039;ll question what civic hacking means in a city like Detroit, where even the semblances of democratic participation are being erased through emergency financial management laws.  We will brainstorm the technologies we need to support emerging infrastructures of self-governance in Detroit and beyond.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 157 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Geoff Hing; Joshua Breitbart, Open Technology Institute, New America Foundation; Maria Hadden, Participatory Budgeting Project; Jenny Lee, Allied Media Projects; Matt Hampel, Code For America</presorgs>
    <seshtype>strategy session</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#civichack</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7001</shortlink>
    <tracks>Webmaking Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Go Fish: Role-playing Food Justice</title>
    <shortdesc>This workshop presents a role-playing game designed to introduce players to the issue of fish consumption and contamination on the Great Lakes. Players are placed in families of anglers, each of which represents a real community with unique socio-economic and cultural factors that influence their consumption decisions. Players &#34;go fishing,&#34; and at the end of the game, receive a score that represents their level of chemical exposure. The workshop will conclude with a discussion and critique of the game.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 1243 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Katy Brown, Buffalo Niagara Riverkeeper; Jordan Dalton, Department of Media Study, University at Buffalo; Paul Lloyd Sargent, Department of Media Study, University at Buffalo; Sarah Cunningham, Buffalo Niagara Riverkeeper; Joel Brenden, Super Giant</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#gofish</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7024</shortlink>
    <tracks>Research Justice Track, Imagining Better Futures Through Play Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Celebrating Our Stories with Comics</title>
    <shortdesc>Can your writing use an extra punch?  Do you have something unique to say that words can’t quite express? Delve into the world of graphic novels, where your imagination comes alive. You decide how your story unfolds in this hands on workshop. Come learn ways to create your very own graphic novella and see examples of powerful storytelling.  Through collective comic making, theatre, writing and drawing exercises, we will work together to bring forth a voice that is truly your own. In this supportive space, everyone will be encouraged to share openly and provide peer feedback. The workshop will be facilitated by young South Asian women, who come have together to share stories, heal and create through the IZZAT Project. This expressive arts project combines illustration, writing and theatre to amplify South Asian young women’s stories of resilience in the face of violence culminating in the creation of a graphic novella.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room M (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Siva-Jeevini Sivarajah, IZZAT Project, Pomegante Tree Group; Aruba Ahmed, IZZAT Project, Pomegranate Tree Group; Farrah Khan, Pomegranate Tree Group; Nadia, IZZAT Project, Pomegranate Tree Group; Shamima, IZZAT Project, Pomegranate Tree Group</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#comicsAMC</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7039</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Healing Justice Practice Space, Imagining Better Futures Through Play Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>ROC&#039;s Political Education for Research</title>
    <shortdesc>Training for community-based researchers often focuses on the fact that community members are more appropriate researchers than far-removed academics. However, the Restaurant Opportunities Center, a national restaurant workers’ organization in 9 cities with 15 industry reports, focuses on the pernicious nature of what our opponents are saying and the way they use flawed research to increase their power to exploit restaurant workers. Research as self-defense communicates urgency to our members. We will impart ROC’s experience and participants will frame their own political education for researchers.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 2242 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Jonathan Hogstad, ROC-United; Teofilo Reyes, ROC-United</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#rschpleduc</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7058</shortlink>
    <tracks>Research Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Streaming Social Movements</title>
    <shortdesc>Want to start broadcasting, right now? You don&#039;t need a radio signal, just a webstream. With just an Internet connection, a few open source programs, and some rubber bands and glue, you can connect your voice and your programs to web listeners (rubber bands and glue are optional). In this bilingual workshop we will learn free, open source tools to create our own webstreams. We will set up a mountpoint, connect an audio interface, and start streaming live.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room L (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Lisa Matuska, Radios Populares</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#streaming</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7150</shortlink>
    <tracks>Occupy the Airwaves! Community Radio Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Upping the Game of DIY Video and Film</title>
    <shortdesc>This workshop will convey basic knowledge about quality control and video production for activists.  Although primarily a hands-on skill share, there will also be discussion of fundraising and distribution.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room B/C (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Amy Oden, From the Back of the Room Productions, George Washington University</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#diyfilm</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7088</shortlink>
    <tracks>Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Worker-Owned Webmaking: Tech Co-ops</title>
    <shortdesc>In this session, we will share our experiences of working in tech cooperatives: how we started, how we operate, the advantages and challenges of building democratic workplaces, and why we love our jobs. We will also explore how the technology we create demonstrates our values of democracy and social justice, and how functioning as worker co-ops builds stronger, more collaborative relationships and movements.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room J (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Raeanne Young, Quilted; Poonam Whabi, Design Action Collective; Jack Aponte, Palante Technology</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#techcoop</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7101</shortlink>
    <tracks>Webmaking Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Making Community Radio</title>
    <shortdesc>Let&#039;s make community radio and DIY and DIT (Do It Yourself and Do It Together).
We will explore a full spectrum of ways to nurture a participatory radio station with very little money.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry C (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Autumn Chacon, Available Media Incorporated; Ryan Dennison, Available Media Incorporated and Rezkids; Sabrina Roach, Brown Paper Tickets</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#How2Radio</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7114</shortlink>
    <tracks>Occupy the Airwaves! Community Radio Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Detroit Sound Conservancy Music Tour</title>
    <shortdesc>Is cultural tourism inevitably a force of gentrification? As many post-industrial cities attempt to capitalize on their cultural economies, what are the concerns of those who may be exposed through cultural heritage tourism? Are those that created (and continue to create) distinct cultural assets also the ones creating cultural heritage tours? If not, why not? If so, how are they interested in shaping these tours? On this off-site driving tour of legendary Detroit music locations AMC attendees will explore the soundscape of Detroit&#039;s music history through the stories of a carefully selected group of Detroit&#039;s musical griots. During the tour, attendees will also exercise story-mapping through the use of mobile applications such as Broadcastr to record and web-post these place-based stories. These posts will then be backed up by the all-volunteer DetroitWiki Project where a visual representation of Detroit&#039;s musical assets will be made available for reflection after the tour. In addition to the tour&#039;s Detroit music griots, this event will be led by Jocelyne Ninneman of Pont Productions and Carleton Gholz of the Detroit Sound Conservancy. Both Jocelyne and Carleton are native Detroit refugees as well as longtime fans and participants in Detroit&#039;s rich music-making culture.  This tour will last two session blocks, arriving back at McGregor at 5:30pm.</shortdesc>
    <location>North Side of McGregor</location>
    <presorgs>Jocelyne M. Ninneman, Pont:Productions / Gris Gris Lab / Detroit Sound Conservancy; Carleton S. Gholz, Detroit Sound Conservancy</presorgs>
    <seshtype>Detroit tours</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCMusic</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7143</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Research Justice Track, Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Transformative Art Open Studio - 1</title>
    <shortdesc>The Transformative Art Practice Space will have open studio time for participants to continue work from other sessions, print track graphics and find additional resources.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 156/158 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#taopen</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7181</shortlink>
    <tracks>Transformative Art Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Healing Justice Individual Session 5</title>
    <shortdesc>Come to the HJPS for Individual Session 5 offering Energy healing, Acupuncture, Massage, Card Readings, and Counseling.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room F/G (McGregor)</location>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCHeal</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7189</shortlink>
    <tracks>Healing Justice Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Outdoor Games for Love and Liberation</title>
    <shortdesc>Join us for some playground games that are life-alteringly fun! These games
will help us practice the ways we want to care for each other and have fun together.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room E (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Ileana Mendez-Penate, &#34;Kids Transform the World!&#34; Practice Space</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for kids!</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#amckids</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7202</shortlink>
    <tracks>Kids Transform The World</tracks>
    <schedblock>2:00pm - 3:30pm / Block 7</schedblock>
    <title>Making Revolutionary Video Games with Verbs</title>
    <shortdesc>Want to make a videogame, but don&#039;t know where to begin? Try starting with something we&#039;re all familiar with: verbs! Whether it&#039;s running or collecting, games are driven by verbs. In this session we&#039;ll look at games in terms of actions and explore how these actions express the messages and values of the game creators. We&#039;ll identify the verbs used in popular games and what these verbs say. Then we&#039;ll modify (&#34;mod&#34;) these games, changing the verbs so they express our own messages and values. This is a paper prototyping session — there will be no computers and no programming!</shortdesc>
    <location>Room M (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Paolo Pedercini, Molleindustria; Una Lee, Imagining Better Futures Through Play</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#gameverbs</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7013</shortlink>
    <tracks>Imagining Better Futures Through Play Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Presented in 4D</title>
    <shortdesc>This presentation will be an artist talk by Autumn Chacon, highlighting current her installation, &#34;Presented in 4D.&#34; Autumn will offer a presentation of food as if it is a musical score yet the final product is still edible.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room B/C (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>autumn chacon, Small Engine Gallery</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>##4D</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6990</shortlink>
    <tracks>Transformative Art Practice Space, Analog Media Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Securing Our Online Communications</title>
    <shortdesc>The AMC is creating its own Web of Trust. As civil society organizations increasingly use personal computers and online communication tools, they are becoming more prone to ever-advancing threats like malware, attacks on Occupy and Anonymous, to legalized digital surveillance in the SOPA and CISPA bills, and even the seizure of equipment. This workshop will raise awareness on the vulnerabilities of digital communication, to introduce simple, low-cost tools to promote privacy and security in participants&#039; organizations, primarily from the perspective of women&#039;s rights.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 157 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Mallory Knodel, Association for Progressive Communications; Josh King, The Open Technology Institute; Preston Rhea, The Open Technology Institute; Lisa Cyr, Association for Progressive Communications</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>##cyrsoc</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7026</shortlink>
    <tracks>Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space, Media Policy for Love and Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Booklove Brainstorm: How We Dialogue</title>
    <shortdesc>It is the digital age and ostensibly we&#039;re running out of trees (and somehow not out of tiny computerized parts). We still long to make those corners into dog ears, to have big shelves full of books keeping us intellectually warm, to see each other in person, to have conversations about our politics that are more dynamic in tone than italics, bold, or witty hashtags. Don&#039;t we? (#thingsnerdshopefor) In this session, we will discuss how to create alternative spaces to talk about books and zines, like community book clubs, anti-racist study groups, and homegrown feminist poetry workshops. We will brainstorm what skills can be gained from face-to-face (or Skyped in) dialogue about radical thought.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 1243 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>jade brooks, make/shift magazine, duke university press, southerners on new ground</presorgs>
    <seshtype>strategy session</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#BookLove!</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7031</shortlink>
    <tracks>Analog Media Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Medios Caminantes: Border Crossing Media</title>
    <shortdesc>In our bilingual session we will feature  audio pieces and show some of the posters that were part of our Know Yr Rights poster series, along with peoples experiences in the network. 

We will feature a video conference with media collective Koman Ilel,who use livestream, podcasts and small fm stations to promote dignity and autonomy in Southern Meico. We will also feature either a video conference or show videos created by Radio collectives in Venezuela, Ecuador and Chile.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 2242 (Keith Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Ana Martina, Prometheus Radio Project; Koman Ilel, Koman Ilel; Andalusia Knoll, Families for Freedom/ Medios Caminantes</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#amcmedios</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7053</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Research Justice Track, Occupy the Airwaves! Community Radio Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Making Community Makerspaces</title>
    <shortdesc>Thanks to the explosive growth of the Internet, the open source hardware &#38; software movement, and innovations in inexpensive tools for making, we can now learn and make things more effectively than ever before. Makerspaces offer the space, tools, and resources to help facilitate enjoyable making and learning together. But how do you start and sustain a Makerspace? How can Makerspaces solve problems and &#34;make&#34; postive change? By considering existing models and brainstorming on new ones, we will also explore new ways for Makerspaces to connect people and amplify talents.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room L (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Jeff Sturges, Mt Elliott Makerspace; Raven Holston, Mt Elliott Makerspace; Ife Zuri, Mt Elliott Makerspace</presorgs>
    <seshtype>strategy session</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#makerspace</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7055</shortlink>
    <tracks>Collective Access Practice Space, Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space, Imagining Better Futures Through Play Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Your Media Rights: A Game Show</title>
    <shortdesc>Come on down and be the next contestant/dissident in our interactive game show about media reform, media policy, and media justice! Players and hosts will teach each other their media rights and break through media policy wonkery using humor, creativity, and good old fashioned game show technique! Through games we will strengthen our collective know-how to protect and advocate for the kind of media we want to see in the world. Attendees will learn about their media rights, create new messages to send out into the world, and help organize for media justice!</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry B (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Carlos Pareja, People&#039;s Production House; Candace Clement, Free Press; Brandy Doyle, Prometheus Radio Project</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#MediaFun</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7063</shortlink>
    <tracks>Media Policy for Love and Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Non-Toxic Tactics for Online Communities</title>
    <shortdesc>How can we make online communities safer, more emotionally supportive, or even liberatory? This interactive brainstorming discussion is for anyone who manages or participates in an online community. It might be the comments section of your own blog, a Tumblr neighbourhood or any other corner of the Internet you call home. We&#039;ll explore practical ways to practice self-care, deal with conflicts, &#34;call-outs,&#34; and more. We&#039;ll also reflect on what community and accountability might look like online, and how to subvert or transcend the unique challenges of online interaction.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry C (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Pixelpowrrr, Pixelpowrrr</presorgs>
    <seshtype>strategy session</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>adults only</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#tactics</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7070</shortlink>
    <tracks>Webmaking Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Performance Fishbowl: Identity &#38; Community</title>
    <shortdesc>This performance fishbowl will include several groups sharing 20 minute excerpts of work that address the role of performance arts in exploring identity and building community, followed by a 30 minute large group discussion about performance content, group structure, and creative process. Featuring JoAnna Hazel Norris of CSketches, Byron Jose, and Jarochicanos.</shortdesc>
    <location>Community Arts Auditorium</location>
    <presorgs>Jo Anna Hazel Norris, Choreographic Sketches; Byron Jose, qteam; Jarochicanos, Jarochicanos</presorgs>
    <seshtype>performance</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>adults only</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCmove</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7085</shortlink>
    <tracks>Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Rap Life! with Media Technologies</title>
    <shortdesc>&#34;Its been a long time comin, tryin 2 make somethin outta nothin, pushin buttons. Connected 2 my people thru these speakers &#38; these cables, blank face clownz shootin&#039; at us with their fables...but the time frame is our mind state, hip hop bangs, vibrates, transforms, bring change.&#34; Everyone is a rapper. Rap comes in many forms. It is important as human beings to rap the stories of our peoples &#38; document the history we leave on Mother Earth. We will share storytelling techniques using media arts &#38; technologies, &#38; show examples to tell your community&#039;s beautiful stories.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 154 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <presorgs>Christopher Yepez (Sacramento Knoxx), AIHFS, DHDC, IYEP, GEAR-UP; Eddi Gonzales (dPress/mad Bars), DHDC; Sara Vitale, MEchA</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#RapLife</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7146</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation)</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>You Can Think AND Dance: for DJs, promoters and partiers</title>
    <shortdesc>Creating social change is about changing social interactions. We want to better understand why dancing/socializing is so critical to our lives and how to do them in a just, creative, and collaborative way. We especially want to unpack how &#34;apolitical&#34; (even anti-political) music/performance can be subversive. Let&#039;s dissect patriarchy, racism, homophobia, and more in parties and music, and battle them on the dancefloor. Dirty Dancing, Raunchy Lyrics, Reclaiming Space and Media, OH MY!</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry A (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>dj bent, Anthology of Booty, Maracuyeah! DC, DJ Geekout; Nina Walia aka Miss Modular/Niña Colada, Subcontinental Drift, DJ Geekout</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#dancethink</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7106</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Movement // Movement Dance Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Crip/Sick Sex Panel</title>
    <shortdesc>What does it mean to &#34;crip&#34; sex? As disabled people who are also queer and gender non-conforming, people of color and indigenous, women, rural, and poor/working class, our bodies are seen as undesirable and we are desexualized. Often we are told we are too unstable or too burdensome to be in a relationship with because of our disabilities and because we have experienced trauma. In this workshop, we will share strategies for resisting isolation and desexualization, explore our embodied experiences, and discuss a variety of issues related to sexuality and disability.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room J (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>A&#039;ishah Hils, National Youth Leadership Network; Savannah Nicole Logsdon-Breakstone, National Youth Leadership Network; billie rain; Leah Lakshmi Piepzna-Samarasinha; Austin J. Austin; Patty Berne, Sins Invalid; Leroy Moore, Sins Invalid</presorgs>
    <seshtype>panel or presentation</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>adults only</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#cripsex</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7128</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Collective Access Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Transformative Art Open Studio - 2</title>
    <shortdesc>The Transformative Art Practice Space will have open studio time for participants to continue work from other sessions, print track graphics and find additional resources.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room 156/158 (Art Ed. Classrooms)</location>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>##TAAMC</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7180</shortlink>
    <tracks>Transformative Art Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Healing Justice Individual Session 6</title>
    <shortdesc>Come to the HJPS during Individual Session 6 on card reading, energy healing, acupuncture, Somatic Bodywork, Reiki, Herbalism, Self-restoration, self-exams and counseling.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room F/G (McGregor)</location>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCHeal</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7190</shortlink>
    <tracks>Healing Justice Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Detroit Sound Conservancy Music Tour (Continued)</title>
    <shortdesc>On this guided off-site driving tour of legendary Detroit music places, we will explore the landscape of Detroit&#039;s music history through the stories of some of the city&#039;s music griots at each location. We will also exercise story-mapping along the way through use of open-source mobile applications such as Broadcastr to record and web-post these place-based stories to a Detroit wiki page, where a visual representation of Detroit&#039;s musical assets will be made available for reflection after the tour. The tour will be led by Jocelyne Ninneman and Carleton Gholz of the Detroit Sound Conservancy, a local organization dedicated to the preservation of Detroit&#039;s steep musical heritage places, artifacts, and people.</shortdesc>
    <location>Off-site</location>
    <presorgs>Jocelyne M. Ninneman, Pont:Productions / Gris Gris Lab / Detroit Sound Conservancy; Carleton S. Gholz, Detroit Sound Conservancy</presorgs>
    <seshtype>Detroit tours</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCMusic</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7243</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Research Justice Track, Media A GoGo Hands-on Technology Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>4:00pm - 5:30pm / Block 8</schedblock>
    <title>Reentry 101: What&#039;s It All About?</title>
    <shortdesc>People returning from corrections will be meeting to caucus and talk about self-determination and their needs post-release.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room L (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Ma Heinen, SOROS Justice Fellow, Master of Social Work Candidate 2012, University of Michigan</presorgs>
    <seshtype>2 hour caucus (dinner-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#REENTRY101</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/6988</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation)</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Queer People of Color Tumblr Meet Up</title>
    <shortdesc>In this caucus, queer people of color will come together to discuss our experiences navigating this interesting arena of online space that so heavily mimics the complexities of IRL queer organizing communities, in power dynamics and more, called Tumblr. We will leave hopefully having answered these questions: What do networks of survival look like for people of color navigating online blogging space? What does solidarity with other people of color, specifically against anti-Black racism, look like in tumblr space? And more!</shortdesc>
    <location>Memorial Hall (Cass Community Commons)</location>
    <presorgs>Cortez Wright, SPARK Reproductive Justice NOW</presorgs>
    <seshtype>1 hour caucus (lunch-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>##qpoctumbl</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7025</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation)</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>POCQY: Coming Out by Going Back in</title>
    <shortdesc>How do we respect and celebrate our traditions growing up as POC and QY? How do we synthesize being POCQY? How are we actively pursuing true representation in the media as POCQY? We will identify stereotypes that have been historically oppressive among POCQY. We will use different media forms to share our messages and create a shared narrative. We&#039;ll leave with tools for having conversations about cultural identity, support from other POCQY, and ways to inspire other POCQY to be fierce and fearless in their identities and proud of their culture.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room M (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Kay Cuajunco, Student Farmworker Alliance; Hải Võ (Hai Vo), Live Real</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#amcpocqy</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7065</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Healing Justice Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Research Justice Caucus</title>
    <shortdesc>For AMC attendees interested in research justice to learn more about existing research justice endeavors, identify current research needs and where sources of support may come from. Given that both researchers and non-researchers will be in the room, this caucus aims at connecting the two, as well as strengthening a developing network of research justice oriented thinkers and doers.</shortdesc>
    <location>Cass Cafe</location>
    <presorgs>Joe Aawesome</presorgs>
    <seshtype>2 hour caucus (dinner-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#rjustice</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7075</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation)</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Strategies for Parenting Older Kids</title>
    <shortdesc>This is a space for discussion amongst activists, organizers, and media makers that also face the challenge of parenting older children (8-14). How do we continue our involvement as activists, organizers, and media makers while also facing the challenges of parenting older kids? How do we counter detrimental messages from the mainstream media that our kids encounter and be more intentional about what we say/do/model? How do we involve our kids in meaningful ways?</shortdesc>
    <location>Good Girls Go to Paris Creperie</location>
    <presorgs>chiara galimberti; Vikki Law</presorgs>
    <seshtype>2 hour caucus (dinner-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#parenting</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7091</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation)</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Intergenerational Farm-to-Fork Dinner</title>
    <shortdesc>Calling all youth, adults, and elders who have a healthy appetite for real food, real talk, and real connections with each other and Mother Earth.  Join us to learn more about one of the many urban agriculture and community kitchen initiatives in Detroit.  Share in the preparation of a meal featuring all locally grown produce, and bring your passion for food justice media to support the radical notion that we are what we eat!  Help us color outside the lines of corporate food narratives so we can break bread together for community empowerment.</shortdesc>
    <location>Memorial Hall (Cass Community Commons)</location>
    <presorgs>Angela and Gregg Newsom, People&#039;s Kitchen; Lottie Spady, Detroit Food Justice Task Force; Sanaa Niajoy, Eco Media Practice Space</presorgs>
    <seshtype>hands-on workshop</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#foodjustus</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7117</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Eco Media Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Black (Fe)masculinity &#38; Online Media</title>
    <shortdesc>Join in on a discussion, led by Ryann Holmes, co-founder of bklyn boihood, that will explore what it means to be accountable when we represent ourselves and our organizations as masculine of center*, female bodied people of color on online media platforms. Participants will be able to continue to explore new definitions of representations of masculinity and femininity, takeaway tools for successful social strategy, skills in branding and messaging, and new connections to collaborate with.</shortdesc>
    <location>Room J (McGregor)</location>
    <presorgs>Ryann Holmes, bklyn boihood</presorgs>
    <seshtype>1 hour caucus (lunch-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>not for kids</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#boisonline</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7139</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation), Transformative Art Practice Space, Media Policy for Love and Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>Healing Justice Saturday Dinnertime Caucus</title>
    <shortdesc>Join the Healing Justice Practice Space for a Lunchtime Caucus discussing skills, ideas and experiences for healing justice advocates.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry B (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Adaku Utah, Healing Justice Practice Space</presorgs>
    <seshtype>2 hour caucus (dinner-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCHeal</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7275</shortlink>
    <tracks>Healing Justice Practice Space</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>MAG-Net and Free Press Mixer</title>
    <shortdesc>Join MAG-Net and Free Press for a Media Policy for Love and Justice mixer. We&#039;ll talk about our ideas, plans, visions and needs in media, policy and social justice. Join this powerful gathering of media makers, journalists, students, researchers, and policy-makers as we network and build powerful conversations.</shortdesc>
    <location>Hilberry A (Student Center)</location>
    <presorgs>Betty Yu, Media Policy for Love and Justice Track</presorgs>
    <seshtype>2 hour caucus (dinner-time)</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>for all ages</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCMPFLJ</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7285</shortlink>
    <tracks>Media Policy for Love and Justice Track</tracks>
    <schedblock>5:30pm - 8:00pm / SAT DINNER BREAK</schedblock>
    <title>AMC2012 Music Showcase</title>
    <shortdesc>Performances by JD Samson &#38; MEN (ex Le Tigre / electropop), Lauren Flax (house), The Black Opera (hip-hop), Emily Wells (classical/electronics), Waajeed (hip-hop/experimental). All Ages. Wheelchair Accessible. Free to registered AMC participants. Museum of Contemporary Art Detroit (MOCAD), 4454 Woodward Ave.</shortdesc>
    <location>MOCAD</location>
    <presorgs>Allied Media Conference</presorgs>
    <seshtype>performance</seshtype>
    <kidfriendliness>adults only</kidfriendliness>
    <hashtag>#AMCmusic</hashtag>
    <shortlink>http://talk.alliedmedia.org/node/7253</shortlink>
    <tracks>General (no track or practice space affiliation)</tracks>
    <schedblock>8:00pm - 2:00am / AMC2012 Music Showcase</schedblock>
  </flow>
</sessions>
